SHAHAR STON

+972-52-3761-865



SW Team lead & Engineer

shaharston@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/shahar-ston



TL;DR

Proven fast learner, highly motivated, creative problem solver and open-minded leader with a commitment to continuous improvement.

3+ years as a Software Team Lead, successfully managed the core team in a fast-paced startup, Leading 6 software engineers and 2 QA engineers.

8+ years as a SW engineer, Architected and developed a high-scale, low-latency networking solution based on microservices, enabling remote vehicle operation at production and on a large scale,

Led development of advanced **cybersecurity** solutions, combining deep research and innovation to deliver pinpoint defenses with minimal impact on customer environments.

Conducted POCs and developed prototypes for imaging sensors, delivered innovative solutions for next-gen technologies.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

- HO Team leader with a passion for people grows, pushing forward, and taking feature from thoughts to production.
- Software engineering, leading high scale SOLID designs and architecture.
- Master of proof of concept projects, proven ability to take an idea and make the idea possible.
- Modern C++ Ninja (C++17), python, bash
- Network & security expert:
 - IP routing, iptables, Netfilter, firewall configuration. network solution architecture
 - o and implementation. TCP/UDP, NAT traversal, VPN tunnels, Load Balancing,
 - o LTE/5G networks. Cybersecurity fundamentals, secure channel creation
 - o (DTLS, TLS), Security agents.
- Software Development and tool:
 - o gRPC, Kafka, ZMQ, Protocol Buffers.
 - o Microservices, Docker, AWS, GCP,
 - CMake, Conan, Git, Jenkins.
 - o Automotive-grade lockless algorithms.

EDUCATION & HONORS

Technion - Israel Institute of Technology

Bachelor's Degree in Electrical & software engineering, 2013-2018

dean's list 2017

President's Award for Excellent Soldiers top 120 soldiers in recognition of exceptional performance and dedication 2010.

Youngest at time

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software engineer Team Lead (started senior SW) Ottopia - driving remote vehicles | 2021 - Present

- Leading the core technology team, specializing in networking, control and data path,
- Hands ON manager of 6 SW engineers and 2 QA engineers.
- Developing automotive grade network solutions to enable remote drive vehicles.
- Designed and implemented a UDP-based relay server handling lowlatency autonomous vehicle telemetry over LTE/5G networks enabling remote driving.
- Deep knowledge in Linux systems, networking, iptables, DNS, loadbalancing, micro services, dockers, Kafka.
- Developing in high throughput low latency environment, lockless algorithms and hight automotive grade standards,
- Build a team from zero to hero, creating processes, SW life cycle, requirements to production, design process, teamwork, mentoring, personal developments program for each member of the team
- Act as PO (product owner) for the team, building requirements and high level designs.
- Working with customers to insure best integration and lowest friction.

Software engineer - cybersecurity

Imperva 2019-2021

- · Leading the Research of new Bigdata DBs and developing an allaround solution to secure client data and intercept network
- Developing a high efficient and low memory consumption solution to minimize the agent impact on the customer DB SQL & NON SQL.
- Specialize in Linux based systems, coding in C++, C and Java.

POC Software engineer

Samsung Israel R&D center | 2017 - 2019

- High-level programmer developing a PoC software's solution for image processing and computer vision algorithms coding in C++, Python, MATLAB.
- · Conducting broad research on state-of-the-art technologies to prove future concepts and to accelerate and enhance performance.
- Create a real solution to future DVS sensors.

Student SW engineer - RT embedded

Rafael Advanced Defense Systems 2015- 2017